(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-07T22:59:08.050927",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
周防パトラ 誕生3Dライブ 2025
Suou Patra Birthday 3D Live 2025
ゲスト: FUWAMOCO
Guest: FUWAMOCO
3D新髪型お披露目
3D New Hairstyle Reveal
重大発表あり！
Important Announcement!
もえあがれ
Burn up!
もえあがれ ガンダム
Burn up, Gundam!
君よ
You...
走れ
Run!
まだ怒りに燃える
If you still have fighting spirit...
闘志があるなら
...burning with anger,
巨大な敵を
strike down the giant enemy!
撃てよ 撃てよ 撃てよ
Strike! Strike! Strike!
正義の怒りをぶつけろ ガンダム
Unleash your righteous anger, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam...
ガンダム
Gundam!
立ち上がれ
Stand up!
立ち上がれ ガンダム
Stand up, Gundam!
君よ
You...
叫べ
Shout!
まだ絶望に沈む
If you still have sorrow...
悲しみあるなら
...sinking in despair,
恐怖をはらって
cast away your fears...
行けよ 行けよ 行けよ
Go! Go! Go!
うずまく血潮を燃やせ ガンダム
Burn your swirling lifeblood, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam...
ガンダム
Gundam!
みなさーん！
Everyone!
周防パトラ誕生日3Dライブお越しいただいてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Suou Patra's Birthday 3D Live!
パトラ、いきます！
Patra, here I go!
甦る
Revive!
甦る ガンダム
Revive, Gundam!
君よ
You...
掴め
Seize it!
まだ愛にふるえる
If you still have a heart...
心があるなら
...trembling with love,
平和を求めて
in search of peace...
翔べよ 翔べよ 翔べよ
Fly! Fly! Fly!
銀河へ向かって 翔べよ ガンダム
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam...
ガンダム
Gundam!
魂が震い立つような、この力...
This power... It makes my very soul tremble...
次々に甦る、歴戦の記憶...
Memories of countless battles return to me one after another...
これは、先代たちの...
These are... my predecessors'...
今、受け継ごう...
Now, I shall inherit them...
おにゅーのパトラの、力と記憶を！
The power and memories of the brand-new Patra!
はい！ということで！
Yes! And with that!
最新個体、周防パトラでーすわー！
I am the latest unit, Suou Patra!
今回も、豪華ステージ！そして、新衣装！
This time too, we have a gorgeous stage and a brand-new outfit!
さらに、巨大カニカマもいるよ！ということで、
And we even have a giant crab stick! So...
ということで
So anyway...
改めまして こんばんはー！
Once again, good evening!
周防パトラ生誕祭お越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Suou Patra's birthday celebration!
はい！
Yes!
見てください まずは新衣装！
Please take a look! First, my new outfit!
気になってる方も多いと思うんですけど
I'm sure many of you have been curious about it.
あ 椅子の方が気になりますが これはロマンサーⅡです はい！
Ah, you might be curious about the chair, but this is the Romancer II. Yes!
はい！じゃ下からね
All right! Let's start from the bottom.
なんと！
Would you believe it!
はい 靴！
Here are my shoes!
ちゃんと今回も新衣装なんですけど...あ、あちら ヒールがあります！
This is indeed a new outfit, and... ah, there are heels on them!
間違えた！ヒールがあります！
Oops, I misspoke! They have heels!
そして！
And next!
このベルトも可愛いでしょ？
Isn't this belt cute too?
はい！
Yes!
で、今回は鉄壁のスカートになっております！
And this time, it's a completely secure skirt!
結構ね 動いても
So even if I move around a lot,
はい！
yes!
鉄壁で頑丈になっております！
it's super secure and sturdy!
それから、お腹！
Also, look at my belly!
見て見て見て！セクシーでしょ？
Look, look, look! Sexy, right?
そして、ベルトもね、かっちりになっております！
And the belt on top is securely buckled up too!
白衣装の時よりちょっと抑えられてるんでね、揺れが、あの、ちょっと足りないかもしれないんですけど、今回もボインボインでお送りいたします！
Compared to the white outfit, they are held down a bit, so they might not bounce as much, but I'll still show off my boing-boings!
そしてそして、
And also,
じゃーん！ポニーテール！
ta-da! A ponytail!
新髪型になっております！
This is my new hairstyle!
ハートのね、アクセサリーが揺れて可愛いでしょ、これも！
The heart accessory sways so cutely too, right?
ほらほらほら！
Look, look, look!
うーん！
Mmm!
という感じでね、とっても可愛い新衣装になりました！
And that's how it is, a super cute new outfit!
さらに、みんなが気になってると思うんですけど、
Furthermore, I'm sure you're all wondering about this,
はい！
yes!
とぅ！なんと、脱げます！
Ta-da! Believe it or not, I can take this off!
え、これYouTube的に大丈夫かな？まあ大丈夫かな？
Wait, is this okay for YouTube? Well, I guess it's fine!
え、見て見て見て見て！
Whoa, look, look, look, look!
こうね、ハートのくり抜きがあるんですよ。いや、背中の筋がまたセクシーですね！
See, there's a heart cutout here. Also, the line of my back is so sexy!
あ、そうそうそう、今回もね、ちゃんと、はい！
Ah, yes, yes, yes, this time too, indeed, yes!
脇が丸見えになっております！
My armpits are fully visible!
たくさんたくさんスクショ待ってます！
I'm looking forward to tons of screenshots!
はい、ということで、ハッシュタグ「#周防パトラ生誕祭」でよろしくお願いします！
All right, so please share them with the hashtag #SuouPatoraSeitansai!
感想とかね、コメントも待ってるよ。おっ、可愛いコメントいっぱいありがとう！
I'm waiting for your thoughts and comments. Oh, thank you for all the cute comments!
はーい！いっぱいね、撮ってくださいね。ふん、ふん、ふん！
Yay! Take lots of pictures, okay? Mm, mm, mm!
あ、なんかセクシーな格好がどうやればいいのか分からないんだけど、皆さんのスクショテクにお任せします！
Well, I don't really know how to strike a sexy pose, so I'll leave it to your screenshot skills!
じゃあ、早速次の曲いきたいと思います！
Now, let's move right on to the next song!
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) Oh, troubled child of man,
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Even those who are not human,
(Be happy!) 弛まず目指せよ
(Be happy!) strive forward without rest.
(Undead) 生きているんだし
(Undead) Since we are alive after all!
目を逸らした過去も
The past we turned our eyes away from,
退屈な未来も
and the tedious future as well,
カウンセリング やれやれ
it's time for counseling, oh dear.
古今東西 ピースピース
Throughout all times and places, peace, peace!
(Unhappy?)
(Unlucky?)
(Be happy!)
(Undead)
ねえねえ ねえねえ 何だか どうして 戦ってるような そんな気がするの
Hey, hey, somehow, for some reason, I feel like I'm fighting...
触れられない 触れたくもない
An untouchable past that I don't even want to touch,
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
my past self, myself, myself, myself.
もうとっくに死んでる
I'm already long dead,
透明な亡霊と対決
facing a transparent specter.
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep inside those innocent, painful memories,
残念？ もう居ないのに
is it a regret? Even though they're no longer here.
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Oh? Is that one better? How ironic.
透かされているのは 現在の自分？
Is it my current self that is being seen through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense. An indelible label.
Yes! 要は コンプレックス
Yes! In short, it's a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It's as if I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま
Coiled tightly around me,
まだ 離れない
it still won't let go:
在りし日の自分
my former self.
Undead
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead. The chain of you and yourself.
生きていることは 変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて
Don't content yourself
満足するなよ
by resigning to unhappiness.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to even try to be happy.
この世 この世は 奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は 鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
出会って 遭って やっと始まる物語
Meeting, encountering... at last, the story begins.
さあ 人か化物か
Now, is it a human or a monster?
閑話休題 ピースピース
Setting that aside, peace, peace!
Past and future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
カ カ カットイン
C-C-Cut-in!
何だか どうして 未来に なんぞ
Somehow, for some reason, toward the future,
何の希望も ない 期待 出来ない ような気がして
I feel like there is no hope, and I can't expect anything...
もう随分 生きている
I've already lived for quite a long time,
既視感と テンプレで食傷
weary of déjà vu and clichés.
素敵な出来事の 気配もない
There's no sign of any wonderful event.
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Regrettable, the cause and effect of accumulated experience.
形骸化 された神話と 退屈な進化
An empty myth and a boring evolution.
要は 刺激が 欲しいんだ
In short, I want some stimulation.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I've grown tired of it, I've gotten used to it.
なんて 整っていくガイダンス
What orderly guidance.
増える コンプライアンス
Ever-increasing compliance.
蓋 されていくみたい
It feels like a lid is being shut.
吸い尽くして
Drain it completely.
あれも これも どれも
That, this, and all of them...
同じ味がする
...taste exactly the same.
いー！あー！ちゅっ！ちゅっ！
I-! A-! Chu! Chu!
あげる！
I'll give it to you!
しんじゃいない！
I'm not dead!
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and you,
いつ世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
exists in the past, future, and now, in any age.
生きていることを愚直に果たそう
Let's honestly fulfill the act of living,
目指せハッピーエンド
aiming for a happy ending!
あげる！
I'll give it to you!
しんじゃいない！
I'm not dead!
お前に言っているんだ
I'm telling you!
幸せを煌めいて 狂うの？人でなし
Are you going crazy, sparkling with happiness? You monster!
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you just get used to suffering and endure it...
死んでるのと同じ
it's the same as being dead,
屍のあげく
in the end, a corpse.
あげる！
I'll give it to you!
しんじゃいない！
I'm not dead!
悩める人がいる 今日明日問わず 悩もう
There are people worrying... let's worry regardless of today or tomorrow,
悩みまくって目指せよ 生きているんだろう？
worry all you want and aim forward! You are alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るな！
Don't drown in misfortune!
幸せに生きるのも
Becoming happy is also...
全部全部お前だ！
entirely up to you!
この舞台勝ちゃ 死ねばハッピーピース
If we win on this stage, even in death, happy peace!
バン！ぶちゅっぱ！キャプテンザバン！
Bang! Buchuppa! Captain the bang!
バン！ぶちゅっぱ！ラブフォースザバン！
Bang! Buchuppa! Love force the bang!
人であるところ
For being human,
いつも愚かさと生き抜く
always surviving with foolishness,
この化け物ばかりの物語
in this story full of monsters.
ちゃっかりしっかり、誕生日グッズのお知らせだよ！
Here's a quick and reliable announcement of my birthday goods!
なんと！パトラの立体マウスパッドや、
Guess what! There's a 3D mousepad of Patra,
バスタオル！
a bath towel!
そして、とっても可愛いアクリルスタンド！
And a super cute acrylic stand,
A4サイズクリアファイル！
an A4 size clear file...
いろんなグッズがある誕生日グッズが登場だよ！
various kinds of birthday goods are now available!
受注生産なので、売り切れの心配ナッシング！
Since they are made-to-order, no need to worry about them selling out!
8月30日までの受付です！
Orders are accepted until August 30th!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
FINAL FANTASY V ビッグブリッヂの死闘
[FINAL FANTASY V: Battle on the Big Bridge]
UNDERTALE Megalovania
ロマンシング サ・ガ2 七英雄バトル
[Romancing SaGa 2: Seven Heroes Battle]
ロマンシング サ・ガ2 / 七英雄バトル
Romancing SaGa 2 / Seven Heroes Battle
アーマード・コア4 / Panther
Armored Core 4 / Panther
仮面ライダー サモンライド！ / Break The World
Kamen Rider Summonride! / Break The World
放たれた矢が 標的へ向かうように
Like an arrow released towards its target,
自らの意思を 奮い立たせる
I stir up my own will.
理由などなく
With no reason at all,
そこに宿命あるだけ
there is only destiny.
ただ進む
Simply moving forward,
仲間と共に往く
I go forth with my comrades.
気持ちは一つ
Our hearts are as one.
水面に映る君は
You, reflected on the water's surface,
遠く...
are far away...
開いたゲートを見つめている
Looking at the open gate
果てしなく続く
Continuing endlessly
クリスタルワールド 突き進む 強い
Pushing forward through the Crystal World, with strong...
意志で 限界を打ち破れ
...will, break through the limits!
キミはサモンライド！ 時は満ちて
You summon ride! The time has come
サモンライド！ 意志を宿し
Summon ride! Harbor the will
願いを一つに集め
Gathering our wishes as one
宿命を越えて 突き抜けろ
Break through beyond our destiny!
サモンライド！ 牙を研ぎ澄ます
Summon ride! Sharpening our fangs
サモンライド！ 孤高に舞え
Summon ride! Dance in proud solitude
約束の地へ 駆け抜けろ
Run through to the promised land!
キミはサモンライド！ 時を超えて
You summon ride! Beyond time
サモンライド！ 祈り届け
Summon ride! Let our prayers reach
思いを絆に変えて
Turning our feelings into bonds
一点突破 突き抜けろ
Break through a single point!
サモンライド！ 次元を超え
Summon ride! Crossing dimensions
サモンライド！ すべては今
Summon ride! Everything is now
約束の地へ 駆け抜けろ
Run through to the promised land!
はい！ということで聞いてくれてありがとうございました！
Alright! Thank you so much for listening!
今、何をやってるかというと...
Right now, what I'm doing is...
とってもこの後、可愛いゲストが来るので、フェロモンを出し巻くっていました！
...giving off tons of pheromones, because a very cute guest is coming next!
はぁ、なんかドキドキするな
Sigh, my heart is beating so fast.
それでは、呼びたいと思います！
Now then, I would like to call them out!
本日のスペシャルゲスト、おいで！
Come on out, today's special guests!
ばうばう！
Bau bau!
おっ、きたー！
Oh, they're here!
ばうばうー！パトラ先輩！
Bau bau! Patra-senpai!
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy Birthday!
うわー！ありがとう！かわいい！
Wow! Thank you! So cute!
いや、フワモコちゃんの二人に来てもらいました！
I have the Fuwamoco duo here with me!
じゃ、自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
はい！チワワじゃないよ、フワワだよ！
Yes! I'm not a Chihuahua, I'm Fuwawa!
フワワじゃないよ、モココだよ！
I'm not Fuwawa, I'm Mococo!
ホロライブEnglish -Advent-の、魔界の番犬シスターズ！
From Hololive English -Advent-, the guard dog sisters of the Demon Realm!
二人を合わせて、フワモコです！ばうばう！
And together, we are Fuwamoco! Bau bau!
はは！ばうばう様！はは！ありがたいです！
Haha! Lord Bau Bau! Haha! I'm so grateful!
いや、フワモコちゃんは、パトラがね、ASMRのボイスをね、プロデュースして...
Actually, Patra produced Fuwamoco's ASMR voice lines...
ね、その時、濃厚な時間を過ごさせていただいたんですよね！
...and we spent such an intense, deep time together!
楽しかったです！楽しかった！
It was so much fun! So much fun!
二人のね、ASMRボイス、販売中なので、よろしくお願いします！
Their ASMR voice packs are on sale now, so please check them out!
ありがとう！なんか恥ずかしい！
Thank you! That's kind of embarrassing!
でも今日はパトラの誕生日だから、二人からご褒美がもらえるって聞いたんだけど...
But since today is my birthday, I heard I can get a reward from the two of you...
えっ、ご褒美？聞いてないですけど！
Eh, a reward? We didn't hear about this!
えっ？そんなそんな！
Eh? No way, no way!
せっかくの誕生日だし...
Well, since it's your special birthday...
えー、ご褒美どうしよう？
Hmm, what should the reward be?
ハグとか？
Maybe a hug?
はっ！ハグ！？
What! A hug!?
ハグ、ハグ、いいよ！
A hug, a hug is good!
は、はい！もうどこでも触ってください！ありがとうございます！
Y-Yes! You can touch me anywhere! Thank you so much!
普通のハグです！じゃあ...
It's just a normal hug! Well then...
せーの、ハッピーバースデー！
One, two, Happy Birthday!
あー！幸せ！フワワの方をなんかむにむにしてる！
Ah! I'm so happy! Fuwawa feels so soft and squishy!
もこちゃんは？もこちゃんも！
What about Moko-chan? Moko-chan too!
そこは可愛いからね！
Because she's cute there!
もこちゃんはね、もこちゃん妹なんだから！
Because Moco-chan is the younger sister!
可愛い！可愛い！ぷるぷるぷる...可愛いご褒美だ！
So cute! So cute! What a cute reward!
今日はね、三人でまたね、歌が歌えると！
And today, the three of us get to sing a song together!
やったー！
Yay!
じゃ、ちょっとパトラ露出が激しいので、着ますね。ほい！
Well, Patra is showing a bit too much skin, so I'll put this on. Hop!
可愛い！ありがとう！
Cute! Thank you!
じゃあ、早速いきますか！はい！
Then, shall we get right to it? Yes!
それでは聞いてください！さくらんぼキッス！
Please listen to: Sakuranbo Kiss!
さくらんぼキッス
Sakuranbo Kiss
あれれ？ おかしいな
Oh? How strange
このドキドキは キミの腕の中で あふれだす
This heart pounding overflows inside your arms
ぽろり こぼれた 涙 さくらんぼ
Tears spilled out like cherries
もっと ぎゅっと ずっとしてて☆
Hold me more tightly, forever☆
すき すき すき kiss すき すき すき kiss すき すき すき kiss すき すき kiss ハイハイ!
Love love love kiss! Love love love kiss! Love love love kiss! Love love kiss, yes, yes!
すき すき すき kiss すき すき すき kiss すき すき すき kiss すき すき kiss キュンキュン!
Love love love kiss! Love love love kiss! Love love love kiss! Love love kiss, heart pounding!
まだまだ かな？
Is it not time yet?
キミのハート ちょっと すっぱい？
Is your heart a little sour?
ホント？
Really?
おや おや おや？
Oh my, oh my, oh my?
待ちきれない このままじゃ
I can't wait at this rate
ねぇ、待って～
Hey, wait~
すました 顔 で キメて！ キメて！
Put on a cool face and decide! Decide!
うつむくには やだよ
I hate hanging my head down!
なにげなく ふわっと
Casually and softly...
風に舞わせて
dancing in the wind...
瞳 閉じ近づく
I close my eyes and draw near...
ずっと 好きだったの
I've loved you all along...
内緒だよ
It's a secret...
イェイ！
Yay!
あれれ？ ちいさな胸が
Oh? My small heart...
震えてる
is trembling.
抱きしめられたら 壊れちゃうよ
If you hug me, I might break.
夢で見ていたのより せつないね保存
It's more painful than what I saw in my dreams.
だからもっと そっとしてね
So please, hold me more gently.
ぽろり 涙 こぼれちゃう
Oops, my tears are spilling over.
大人になるための 痛みください
Please give me the pain to grow up.
君に触れられた ほお 染まってく
My cheeks, touched by you, are turning red.
キスは ちょっとだけ待ってね
Please wait just a bit for the kiss.
すき すき すき すき すき
Love, love, love, love, love!
きゅう！
Kyu!
やだやだやだやだ よそ見はやだ
No, no, no, no, don't look away!
もっと あたしだけを 見ていて
Look only at me more!
はらはらはらはら わたしもまだ
Fluttering, fluttering, I am still...
こどもだもん
just a kid!
君の余裕が グサッと
Your calm attitude pierces me...
胸の奥に 刺さるよ
stabs deep into my heart!
この私 スパッと
This side of me, cleanly...
忘れさせてね やさしいキスで
make me forget, with a gentle kiss!
きゅんとしちゃうもん！
My heart is fluttering!
内緒だよ
It's a secret...
イェイ！
Yay!
あれれ？ 唇が
Oh? My lips...
震えてる
are trembling.
君のまつげが 瞳にうつる
Your eyelashes are reflected in my eyes.
鼓動の波打つ 速さ 急上昇
The speed of my beating heart rises rapidly.
だけど超 超 超 幸せ
But I'm super, super, super happy!
小鳥達にも 留まる瞬間に
Even for the birds, in the moment they stop...
壊れそうな心 溶けだす
my fragile heart begins to melt.
赤くはじけたあたし さくらんぼ
I'm a bright red popped cherry...
君とずっと つながっていたい
I want to be connected with you forever.
あ、神様、この唇は、彼と出会うために生まれてきたのですね
Ah, God, these lips were born to meet him, weren't they?
ううう、いぇーい！
Oooooh, yeah!
すまし顔で 決めて
Striking a pose with a cool face...
うわの空は やだよ
I hate when you're spaced out!
なにげなく ふわっと
Casually and softly...
風に舞わせて
dancing in the wind...
瞳 閉じ近づく
I close my eyes and draw near...
あれれ？ おかしいな どきどきは
Oh? How strange, this heartbeat...
君の腕の中で あふれだす
is overflowing inside your arms.
ぽろりこぼれた涙 さくらんぼ
My spilled tears, cherry...
もっとぎゅっと そっとしてて
Please hold me tighter, more gently.
あれれ？ 世界が くるり回る
Oh? The world is spinning round and round...
ふわふわ 夢心地 風まかせ
Fluffy, dreamy, left to the wind...
ずっと待ってた恋は 止まらない
The love I've been waiting for won't stop...
だから ずっと 離さないで
So please, never let me go.
すき すき すき すき すき
Love, love, love, love, love!
きゅう！
Kyu!
おっぱーい！
Oppai!
みんな！
Everyone!
周防パトラ生誕祭、盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for livening up Suou Patra's Birthday Festival!
まだまだ歌っちゃうから、盛り上げ、よろしくおねがいしまーす！
I'm still going to keep singing, so please keep the excitement going!
フー！
Woo!
偉大なる悪魔は実は大天使パトラちゃん様なのだ！
The Great Demon is actually the Archangel Patra-chan-sama!
いくよー！
Here we go!
一生ついてきなさい、ま！
Follow me for life, mwah!
甘やかしてあげちゃうわ
I'll pamper you!
ほらんで きゅんをなくさないで
Look, don't lose that heart flutter!
戦わないもん マスターに負けないで
I won't fight! Don't lose to the master!
きみの運命は
Your destiny...
自分できりひらけ
is to carve out on your own!
バカって言うほうがバカ！
The one who calls others stupid is the stupid one!
超セクシーでキュートで
Super sexy and cute,
だんぜん最強プリティーが
definitely the strongest, prettiest girl!
人類で文化的な最低限のボインボイン
The cultural, minimum required boin-boin of humanity!
いつまいらい！
It's my life!
むにむにむにむに はっぴーむにゅ
Muni muni muni muni, happy munyu!
そもそもこんなにかわいいのに
In the first place, even though I'm this cute...
いつから悪魔と錯覚していた？
Since when did you mistake me for a demon?
そうだそうだ！ パトラちゃんは天使のような女の子！
That's right, that's right! Patra-chan is an angel-like girl!
右に向きおっとりゃいい
If you just turn right, that's fine!
地球が逆回転しとんじゃあない？
Isn't the Earth rotating in reverse?
いつでもいつも主役、いつでもいつも主人公
Always, always the star, always, always the protagonist!
あーなんか疲れたな
Ah, I'm kind of tired...
時代が追いつくまで待とう
Let's wait until the era catches up.
今日も誕生日！
Today is also my birthday!
ちょっと、何で
Hey, why...
よそ見してるのよ
are you looking away?
こんなに大好きなのに
Even though I love you this much...
どういうこと？
what does this mean?
うそうそうそうそ...
Lies, lies, lies...
幸福安心委員会
Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee
全員幸福です！
Everyone is happy!
いいわ 何だか知らん
Fine, I don't know what it is,
今こそ一致団結！
but now is the time to unite!
パトラちゃん様に愛を込めて！
Send your love to Lady Patra!
行くぜ ライブ！
Here we go, live!
行くぜ おーい！
Here we go, oi!
全部全部短いなら書き足そう ソートリスト
If it's too short, let's add to it, sort list.
テンション無駄に高いなら書き足そう ソートリスト
If our energy is needlessly high, let's add to it, sort list.
いい楽しいほうでいいでしょう
It's fine to just have fun, right?
いい？
Good?
行くぜ ライブ！
Here we go, live!
行くぜ おーい！
Here we go, oi!
もっともっと甘えさせて今日
Let me pamper you more and more today.
転んで シーツの中 泣いて
Tumble down, and cry under the sheets.
ただこんなモンスターに負けないで
Just don't lose to a monster like this.
自分の運命は
My own fate is...
自分で切り開け
I will carve out myself!
ばか！自由のほうがばか！
Idiot! Freedom makes you an idiot!
セクシーでキュートで絶対最高！
Sexy, cute, and absolutely the best!
ふりかけ健康で
With a sprinkle of health,
文化的な最低限のポインポイン
and cultured, minimum "poin-poin",
It's my life!
むにむにむにむに ハッピーにゅー
Muni muni muni muni, happy nyuu!
むにむにむにむに ハッピーにゅー！
みんなー！
Everyone!
コメントで応援
Support me in the comments!
どうもありがとう！
Thank you so much!
見えてるよー！
I can see you!
おっ！
Oh!
パトラちゃん可愛いって言ってる？
Are you saying Patra-chan is cute?
ちょっと！そこの君 サボってんじゃないよー！
Hey! You over there, don't slack off!
画面の向こう見えてるぞー！
I can see beyond the screen!
さあさあ！
Come on, come on!
たくさんコメント打ってねー！
Write lots of comments!
笑わせて でも気にしないな
Make me laugh, but I don't care.
そのまま終わるより素晴らしい
That's better than just ending like that,
と誇り
with pride.
おかわりの約束を忘れるな
Don't forget the promise of seconds.
かっこ悪く生きろ
Live uncoolly!
傷ついた思い出に負けない
Not losing to hurt memories,
気分になり
getting in the mood.
みんな 盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for hyping things up!
この後は一緒に「パトラちゃん様」と言ってください！
After this, please say "Lady Patra-chan" together with me!
せーの！
Ready, go!
パトラちゃん様！
Lady Patra-chan!
どうもありがとう！
Thank you so much!
ぴょん！
Pyon!
行くぜ ライブ！
Here we go, live!
行くぜ おーい！
Here we go, oi!
全部全部短いなら書き足そう ソートリスト
If it's too short, let's add to it, sort list.
テンション無駄に高いなら書き足そう ソートリスト
If our energy is needlessly high, let's add to it, sort list.
いい楽しいほうでいいでしょう
It's fine to just have fun, right?
いい？
Good?
行くぜ ライブ！
Here we go, live!
行くぜ おーい！
Here we go, oi!
もっともっと甘えさせて今日
Let me pamper you more and more today.
転んで シーツの中 泣いて
Tumble down, and cry under the sheets.
ただこんなモンスターに負けないで
Just don't lose to a monster like this.
自分の運命は
My own fate is...
自分で切り開け
I will carve out myself!
ばか！自由のほうがばか！
Idiot! Freedom makes you an idiot!
セクシーでキュートで絶対最高！
Sexy, cute, and absolutely the best!
ふりかけ健康で
With a sprinkle of health,
文化的な最低限のポインポイン
and cultured, minimum "poin-poin",
It's my life!
むにむにむにむに ハッピーにゅー
Muni muni muni muni, happy nyuu!
むにむにむにむに ハッピーにゅー！
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
もう一回！
One more time!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
移動してるよ！ちょっと待ってね！
[On-Screen: I'm moving! Please wait a moment!]
はい！
Yes!
皆さん！
Everyone!
ラクス・クラインです！
I am Lacus Clyne!
まだまだ生誕祭 盛り上げていってくださいね！
Please keep hyping up the birthday celebration!
静かなこの夜に
In this quiet night,
あなたを待ってるの
I am waiting for you.
あのとき忘れた 微笑みを取りに来て
Come retrieve the smile you forgot back then.
あれから少しだけ 時間が過ぎて
Just a little time has passed since then,
思い出が優しくなったね
and the memories have become gentle.
イェーイ！
Yay!
星の降る場所で
In the place where stars fall,
あなたが笑っていることを
always hoping that
いつも願ってた
you were smiling.
今遠くても
Though we're far apart now,
また会えるよね
we can meet again, right?
はい！
Yes!
いつから微笑みは こんなに儚くて
When did your smile become so fleeting?
一つの間違いで
Since it was broken
壊れてしまうから
by that one mistake,
大切なものだけを 光にかえて
change only what's precious to you into light.
遠い空越えて行く 強さで
With strength that can cross over the distant sky...
イェーイ！
Yay!
降る場所に
...where they fall,
想いをあなたに届けたい
I want to deliver my thoughts to you.
いつもそばにいる
I'm always by your side,
We are VTuber! ひとりじゃない
We are VTubers! You are not alone.
ドリーミングジャーニー
Dreaming Journey.
歌うから生誕祭があるのではありません。
I don't sing because there is a birthday celebration.
生誕祭があるから歌うのです！
I sing because there is a birthday celebration!
星の降る場所で
At the place where stars fall,
あなたが笑っていることを
that you are smiling...
いつも願ってた
...is what I've always wished for.
今遠くても
Even if we are far apart now,
また会えるよね
we can meet again, right?
星の降る場所に
To the place where stars fall,
想いをあなたに届けたい
I want to deliver my thoughts to you.
いつもそばにいる
I'm always by your side,
We are VTuber! ひとりじゃない
We are VTubers! You are not alone.
ドリーミングジャーニー
Dreaming Journey.
いっぱい聴いてくれて、どうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for listening!
それでは次はお待ちかねのビデオレターです！どうぞ！
Now, next is the long-awaited video message! Here it is!
周防パトラお姉ちゃん！
Suou Patra-oneechan!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
パチパチパチパチ！
Clap, clap, clap, clap!
VTuberの華憐です。
I'm VTuber Karen.
パトラお姉ちゃんは、何度も華憐の番組に出てくれたりして、
Patra-oneechan has appeared on my show many times...
華憐、とってもとっても感謝しています。
...and I'm so, so grateful to you.
最近だと、去年の12月20日の生配信かな？にゲストとして来てくれました！
Most recently, you came as a guest on my live stream on December 20th last year!
華憐、それまでちょっとコールドスリープでお休みしてたんで、
Before that, I was resting in cold sleep for a while,
まさかまたね、パトラお姉ちゃんが華憐の番組に来て、再会できると思ってなかったので、
so I never expected to meet Patra-oneechan again on my show.
もう、すっごくすっごく嬉しかったです！
I was just so, so happy!
その時はパピプペポゲームで盛り上がったりしてましたけど、
At that time, we had a lot of fun playing the Papipupepo Game,
皆さん見てくれたかな？
did everyone watch it?
もし、見てくれてない方は、アーカイブ残ってます！
If you haven't watched it, the archive is still available!
はい、そんなパトラお姉ちゃんには華憐のソロ曲、
Yes, and for Patra-oneechan, my solo song,
「ラブ・メロディー」も、パトラお姉ちゃんに作っていただいて、
Patra-oneechan also made "Love Melody" for me,
華憐ね、いつかパトラお姉ちゃんと一緒に
and I have a dream that one day,
その曲を、なんだろう？デュエットっていうのかな？一緒に歌えたらいいなっていう夢を持っています。
I can sing that song together as a duet with Patra-oneechan.
その夢が叶うように、華憐もこれからも頑張りたいと思います。
To make that dream come true, I'll keep doing my best.
パトラお姉ちゃんもいつまでも体には気をつけて、頑張ってください！
Patra-oneechan, please take care of yourself and keep doing your best!
では、これからの1年もパトラお姉ちゃんにとって
I hope this coming year will be
素敵な素敵な1年になりますように。
a wonderful, wonderful year for you.
パトラお姉ちゃん、大好き！
Patra-oneechan, I love you!
おやすみなさい。
Good night.
パトラちゃん お誕生日おめでとう
Patra-chan, happy birthday!
漫画家・イラストレーターの飯田ぽち。と申します
I'm Pochi Iida, a manga artist and illustrator.
このお仕事をしておりますと 時々 身心ともにエネルギー切れになってね
In this job, sometimes I run out of energy both physically and mentally,
疲れてしまうことも多いんですけれども
and get tired quite often.
そんな時にね いつもパトラちゃんが「新作楽しみにしてます！」「読みました！」「グッズ買いました！」と伝えてくださるので
But whenever that happens, Patra-chan always tells me, "I'm looking forward to your new work!", "I read it!", or "I bought your merchandise!"
いつも私 心の栄養を貰っております
So I always receive nourishment for my soul.
パトラちゃんのおかげで いつも頑張れております いつもありがとう
Thanks to Patra-chan, I can always do my best. Thank you as always!
そんなパトラちゃんの優しさに甘えてしまって 私日頃お世話になりっぱなしですので
I've been spoiling myself with Patra-chan's kindness and always being taken care of,
そろそろね 私からも 何か恩返しをさせてくださいね
so soon, please let me give something back to you too.
いつでもね なんかあったら 気軽に声かけてください
Anytime you need something, feel free to contact me.
というわけで パトラちゃんのますますのご活躍と そして今年が素敵な一年になること 心から願っております
So, I sincerely wish Patra-chan continued success and a wonderful year ahead.
改めて本日は お誕生日おめでとうございます
Once again, happy birthday to you!
飯田ぽち。でした おめでとう
This was Pochi Iida. Congratulations!
パトちゃん！
Pato-chan!
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy Birthday!
お誕生日おめでとう！
にじさんじ所属の...
From Nijisanji...
の、夜見れなです！
...I'm Yorumi Rena!
パトちゃんとはね、なんだかんだつるんで、まあASMR絡みが多いですけど
I end up hanging out with Pat-chan quite a bit, though it's usually ASMR-related.
実は、夜見
But actually, I...
パトちゃんとゲームも一緒にしたいなーって思ってるんだよね
...really want to play games together with Pat-chan too.
なので、今度一緒にゲームで遊んでください！
So please play some games with me next time!
またね、いつめんでご飯も行こうね
Also, let's go grab food with our usual group again.
もちろん、夜見と二人きりでも、いいですけどね
Of course, just the two of us is perfectly fine too.
パトちゃんにとって素敵な1日を過ごしてね
I hope you have a wonderful day, Pat-chan!
ほな、またねー
Well, see you later!
連絡待ってまーす
I'll be waiting for your message!
バイバーイ
Bye-bye!
パトラ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra, happy birthday!
最高の女が、また1秒1秒と、この世に存在を刻んでいるね
The best woman in the world continues to carve her presence into this world, second by second.
このまま永遠に刻んでいってくれよな
Keep on carving it forever, okay?
突然、私事なんですけれど
On a sudden personal note,
最近生活リズムが壊れているんですよね
my sleep schedule has been completely ruined lately.
まあ、今に始まったことじゃないんですけど
Well, it's not like this is anything new, though.
そこで、私は
So, I was thinking...
パトラのおはよう配信から始まって
...starting with Patra's morning streams...
ASMRおやすみ配信で終わる
...and ending with her ASMR sleep streams,
パトラ24が欲しいと思っているんです！
I want a 24-hour Patra stream!
パトラ、一日生活動画が欲しい！
Patra, I want a daily life video!
パトラで、俺の生活を整えたい！
I want to fix my life using Patra!
どうですか？
How about it?
お誕生日、おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
パジョ、誕生日おめでとう！
Pajo, happy birthday!
いやー、誕生日ですか、めでたいですねー
Well, so it's your birthday, how wonderful!
またね、プレゼント渡しに、家行くんだよね？ぜひぜひ入れてください
Also, I'm going to your house to hand you your present, right? Please let me in!
また行くからね、お家。ダラダラしに行くからね。グッズも持って行くからね！
I'll visit your place again to lounge around. I'll bring some merch too!
おめでとう！またね！
Congrats! See you later!
いや、ビデオレターありがとうございました！
Wow, thank you so much for the video letters!
本当にね、いろんな子たちからのビデオレター、ありがたいです。家宝にします！ありがとうございました！
I'm really so grateful for all the video letters from everyone. I'll treasure them forever! Thank you so much!
それではですね、次は、告知になります！
Now then, next up, we have some announcements!
どうぞ！
Here they are!
皆さん、こんちわわ！
Hello, everyone!
周防パトラです！
I'm Suo Patra!
パトダイレクトをご覧いただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for watching Pat-Direct!
今日は全部で4つの告知があります！
Today, I have a total of four announcements!
それではまず、こちらの告知をご覧ください！
First, let's take a look at this announcement!
ギターを教えてみてよ
Teach me how to play the guitar!
コナミ
Konami
この度、アミューズメント施設向けの音楽ゲーム
This time, in the arcade music game series...
GITADORAシリーズのアリーナモデル筐体にて
...'GITADORA', on the Arena Model cabinets...
楽曲収録することになりました！
...my song will be officially included!
なんと曲は、メタル！
And the genre of the song is metal!
BEMANI Sound Team \"あさき\"さんと、ダブルギター！
It features double guitars with BEMANI Sound Team 'Asaki'!
このライブが終わった後、ゲーム内ですぐにプレイできるようになります！
Once this live stream ends, it will be playable in the game immediately!
ゲーム内の「GALAXY WAVE DELTA」カテゴリから選曲してみてね
Try selecting it from the 'GALAXY WAVE DELTA' category!
初めてGITADORAをプレイするよという人は、ルーキーモードでぜひプレイしてみてください！
If you're playing GITADORA for the first time, please try playing in Rookie Mode!
また、19時からコナミ公式YouTubeチャンネルから
Also, starting from 7:00 PM, on the official Konami YouTube channel...
この楽曲のフルバージョンもアップロード予定！
...the full version of this song is scheduled to be uploaded!
皆さん、ぜひGITADORAで遊んでみてね！
Everyone, please go try it out in GITADORA!
やったー！
Yay!
ついに発表！
Finally, the announcement!
周防パトラフィギュア第2弾が登場しちゃいます！
The second Suo Patra figure is on its way!
今回のテーマは
The theme this time...
ASMR配信の世界観を詰め込んだ
...is packed with the world of ASMR streaming,
周防パトラ監修の完全オリジナルポーズ！
featuring a fully original pose supervised by Suo Patra!
髪の毛は透明パーツで毛先まで美しく！
The hair uses translucent parts to look beautiful right down to the tips!
お洋服の艶感、チョーカーやベルトの金具まで忠実に再現！
The texture of the outfit, the choker, and even the belt buckles are faithfully recreated!
おへそ周りのシースルーは、はぁ…ため息もの！
The see-through fabric around the belly button is just breath-taking!
お尻、胸、足裏まで
From the hips, chest, to the soles of the feet,
職人技で丁寧に仕上げました！
it has been carefully crafted with master craftsmanship!
耳かきやクッション、ラグマットも超可愛い！
The ear pick, cushion, and rug are also super cute!
クッションにはパトラのサイン入りだよ！
The cushion even features Patra's signature!
そして、気分で楽しめる表情差し替えパーツ付き！
And it comes with interchangeable face parts to suit your mood!
きゅんと困り顔も楽しんでね！
Enjoy her adorable troubled face too!
受注開始は8月…
Pre-orders start on August...
15日から開始です！
Pre-orders start on the 15th!
予約締め切りは10月17日までだよ！
The pre-order deadline is October 17th!
絶対、ゲットしてね！
Make sure to get yours!
はあ…パトラちゃん
お腹が空いて力が出ないよ…
Sigh... Patra-chan...
I'm so hungry, I have no energy...
そんな時はこれ！
In times like that, try this!
手作り風うめぇ！パトラのかにかまカレー！
Handmade-style, delicious!
Patra's Crab Stick Curry!
ピリッとスパイスのきいたカレーに
かにかまがゴロゴロ！うめぇー！
Spicy, flavorful curry packed
with chunky crab sticks! So good!
（食べる音）おお！
(Eating sounds) Oh!
ギガデリシャスだね！
This is giga-delicious!
ついにでた！周防パトラ全面監修！
手作り風うめぇパトラのかにかまカレー！
It's finally here! Fully supervised by Suou Patra!
Handmade-style, delicious Patra's Crab Stick Curry!
2025年10月1日発売！
On sale October 1, 2025!
1箱に2食入り！パトラのオリジナルカードが
全6種類、1枚入りだよ！
Two servings per box! Includes one of
six collectible Patra cards!
そしてなんと！パトラのUMEEE皿
＆パトラのUMAIスプーンセットも発売だよ！
And that's not all! Patra's UMEEE Plate
& UMAI Spoon Set is also on sale!
スプーンはパトラがイラスト描いたよ！
I drew the illustration on the spoon myself!
栄養満点！パトラの愛情も満点だよ！
Tons of nutrition!
And packed with all of Patra's love!
詳細はまたX等でお知らせするね！
I'll share more details on X
and other platforms!
楽しみにしててねー！
Look forward to it!
全部で3つの告知をご覧いただき
ありがとうございました！
Thank you for tuning in to all
three of these announcements!
ギタドラ、カレー、それからフリューさんでは
第二弾のフィギュアが出ることになりました！
Gitadora, curry, and FURYU is
releasing a second figure line!
楽しみですね！
I can't wait!
それでは、次で最後の告知です。ご覧ください！
And now, for the final announcement.
Please take a look!
「周防パトラ……？」って、だれ？
"Suou Patra...?" Who is that?
企画 周防パトラ
[Planning: Suou Patra]
制作 エンターグラム
[Developer: ENTERGRAM]
記憶をなくしたパトラと君が織りなす、
もしもの物語。
A "what-if" story woven by you
and a Patra who lost her memories.
恋愛アドベンチャーゲーム「君色パトラIF」
ゲーム制作決定！
Romance adventure game "Kimiiro Patra IF"
has been greenlit!
パトラのこと、拾ってくれますか？
Will you take me in?
はーい！ということで盛りだくさんの
告知でしたー！
All right! That was a whole bunch
of announcements!
みんなびっくりした？
Did I surprise everyone?
あとでね、Xの方にも情報を出しますので、
よろしくお願いします！
I'll post all the info on X later,
so please check it out!
そしてね、ここまでたくさん歌ったんですけど、
次でラストの曲になります！
We've sung so many songs today, but the next
one will be the last!
おおー、コメントもたくさんありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you so much for all the comments!
いやーね、今年もこうしてね、新しい3Dが出せたり、
あのー素敵なステージでライブができたのは…
To be able to reveal a new 3D model and perform
on such a wonderful stage this year...
応援してくれてるみんなのおかげです！
...is all thanks to everyone supporting me!
今日もね、ハッシュタグでたくさん呟いてくれて
どうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the hashtag posts
today too!
そして、そして！本日のステージを作って
くださいました、ブレイブグループの皆さん！
本当にありがとうございました！
And also! To everyone at Brave Group
who created today's stage, thank you so much!
すごい！っていうのもあるし、パトラがね、
あのー、スカートの中ね、よく見せちゃうのでね
It's so amazing! Since I tend to...
show off under my skirt a lot,
今日はね、素敵なアングルを考えて撮って
くれました！本当にありがとうございます！
they thought of and filmed from wonderful angles
today! Thank you so much!
はい！それでは！
All right! Well then!
次の曲、なんと新曲になります！
The next song is actually a brand new song!
ぜひ聞いてください！
Please enjoy it!
新曲は、「みんな〜！」
The new song is... "Minna~!"
みんな、みんな、みんな、みんなー！
Everyone, everyone, everyone, everyone!
みんなは噛めば噛むほど味が出るもの
知ってる？
Did you know there's something that gets
tastier the more you chew?
人類の常識を超えて歴史を刻むもの、
教えてあげるね！
I'll teach you about something that transcends
human common sense to carve out history!
みんな！
Everyone!
手拍子するよー！
Let's clap our hands!
気がついたら24時間ゲームばかりしている
Before I knew it, I'd been playing games
for 24 hours straight
現実？幻？夢の中？どういうわけか
やめられない！
Reality? Illusion? A dream?
Somehow I just can't stop!
途中までバフを引いて最初からやり直し
Getting buffs halfway through,
only to restart from the beginning
バグじゃない！夢の中！冷めてもずっと
やめられない！
It's not a bug! I'm in a dream!
Even when I wake, I can't stop!
昔の昔の黒歴史、絶対誰でもあるよ、
あるよ
Ancient, embarrassing dark histories...
absolutely everyone has one, they do
デバッグちゃんと押したのかな？なんて
楽しむ物語、スクリーミラー！
Did I actually press "debug"?
What a fun story, screen mirror!
あの熱心な意味には価値がある！
パトはそう思います！
There's value in that intense dedication!
That's what Pato thinks!
みんな歌え！みんな叫べ！
バグをバグを…
Everyone sing! Everyone shout!
The bug, the bug...
けれどもクソゲー
But it's a crappy game,
なにこれこの世にない
what is this? It doesn't exist in this world.
クリアして見せて笑ってやる
Clear it and I'll laugh with you,
みんな笑え みんな踊れ
everyone laugh, everyone dance!
きっと魅力隠してるんだろう
Surely it's hiding some charm.
ダサいのにね 羨ましい
Even though it's uncool, it's enviable.
そんな風に生きてみたいや
I want to live like that too.
気がついたらみんなみんな
Before we knew it, everyone...
手取り足取り教えてる
...is teaching me step-by-step.
神ゲー？無理ゲー？クソゲー？
God game? Impossible game? Crappy game?
好奇心は止められない
Our curiosity cannot be stopped!
良いことも悪いことも
Both good things and bad things,
君の人生の味方になあれ
will become allies in your life!
みんな怒れ みんな叫べ
Everyone get angry, everyone scream!
ゲームオーバー またリトライ すればいい
It's game over? Just retry again!
諦められない心で
With a heart that refuses to give up,
ハッピーエンドに行こう
let's go to a happy ending!
君も笑え 君も踊れ
You smile too, you dance too!
許すだけが正義じゃないよね
Forgiving isn't the only justice, is it?
暴け白黒
Reveal it, black or white!
悲しい時は泣けばいいんだよ
When you're sad, it's okay to cry!
何そんなふにゃふにゃしたこと言ってるんですか？
What are you saying such weak things for?!
もう、ゴールしてもいいかな？
Can I... reach the goal already?
いやいや、思いを込めたもののすべてを見届けたい
No, no! I want to witness everything that I poured my feelings into.
そんな行く末が見たいだけ！
I just want to see how it ends!
みんなみんな 不安なんだよ 世の中にね
Everyone is feeling anxious in this world.
自分のこと 許してくれる人がいるのかな？
I wonder if there's anyone who will forgive me.
挑戦したら 優勝！
If you try, you win!
みんな怒れ みんな叫べ
Everyone get angry, everyone scream!
バグだらけ 振り切った
Full of bugs, but I shook them off!
けれどもクソゲー なにこれこの世にない
But it's a crappy game, what's this? It doesn't exist in this world!
クリアして見せて笑ってやるんだ
Clear it and show me, and I'll laugh with you!
はーい、お疲れ様でしたー！
Okay, thank you so much for your hard work!
ね、あ、かにかまもいてくれたの？どうもお疲れ様でした！
Oh, Kanikama was here too? Thank you so much for your hard work!
いや、今日はね、あ、みんな！みんな！みんなー！終わってたよ！
Well, today, oh! Everyone! Everyone! Everyone! It finished!
今日はね、あの、なんと！前回と同じステージと思いつつ
Today, surprisingly! While you might think it's the same stage as last time...
ちょっとね変化があるんですよ。ステージの紹介をしたいかなって思います。まだまだあるよ！
...there are actually some changes. I'd like to introduce the stage. There's still more!
見て、見て、見て、見て、これ！なんと、前回よりもプレゼントが増えています！ってことで。
Look, look, look, look at this! Surprisingly, there are more presents than last time!
ほらほらほら、何が入っているのかなっていうね、形になってるのと、
See, see? It makes you wonder what's inside.
あと、ここ！かにかまがちょっと変化してます！わかるでしょうか？
Also, right here! Kanikama has changed a bit! Can you tell?
えー、間違い探しじゃないですけどね、微妙に変わっております。
It's not a spot-the-difference game, but it has changed slightly.
なんと、かにかまが増えています！
Unbelievably, there are more Kanikamas!
気づいた？気づいたかな？あとステージ全体はこうなってます！
Did you notice? I wonder if you noticed. Also, the whole stage looks like this!
おお！豪華！
Oh! It's so gorgeous!
すごいよね。キラキラ度も増しております！
It's amazing. The sparkle level has also increased!
みんなも応援ありがとう！
Thank you everyone for your support!
それからね、でっかいね、サムネイル！かわいい！
And also, the huge thumbnail! It's so cute!
同じ、同じポーズ。なんか違うような気がするけど、あ、同じポーズ！
The same, same pose. I feel like it's a bit different, but oh, the same pose!
ね！すごい豪華に描いてもらいました！
Right? They drew it so beautifully!
それから、あ、あーい！シロパト！
And then... oh! White Patra!
はいはいはいはい。ちょうどね、はい。あんまりね、あの、出番がなかったシロパトちゃんです！
Yes, yes, yes. Exactly. This is White Patra-chan, who didn't get much screen time!
ね、今日はね、1曲目ね、歌ってくれてどうもありがとうね、シロパト！
Thanks for singing the first song today, White Patra!
みんなは、白と黒、どっちのパトラが好き？
Which Patra do you all like, white or black?
あ、ね、あ、シロパトちゃんの方がちょっとね、柔らかいの、ほら跳ねて跳ねて。
Oh, White Patra-chan is a bit softer. Look, bounce, bounce!
そうなの。やっぱりパトはね、あの、胸元のベルトが入ってるからね、シロパトちゃんの方が柔らかいんですよ！
That's right. Because mine has a belt around the chest, White Patra-chan's is softer!
ほらほら、よく見てみて。2人のツーショット、みんな、どっちが好きかな？どっちも好き？
Look closely. Our two-shot. Which one do you like? Both?
あ、ありがとうございます。あ、じゃ、高評価、チャンネル登録もぜひよろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much. Please be sure to give a thumbs up and subscribe!
みんな、本当に今日はありがとう！
Thank you so much for today, everyone!
これからもよろしくね！バイバーイ！
I look forward to your continued support! Bye-bye!
生誕祭ライブ終わりました！
My birthday concert has come to a close!
つたない歌と豪華なステージで はしゃぐパトが
That Patra was able to frolic on a gorgeous stage
今年もできたのは あなたのおかげです。
with her clumsy singing again this year is all thanks to you.
今日もこの世界に生きててくれてありがとう！
Thank you for being alive in this world today!
パトは今皆といることが一番楽しいです。
Being with everyone right now is what brings Patra the most joy.
それはきっと世界で一番幸せなことです。
And that is surely the happiest thing in the world.
周防パトラ誕生日3Dライブ 2025 (新髪型お披露目)
Suou Patra Birthday 3D Live 2025 (New Hairstyle Reveal)